If you're using Windows, you will need to right click blender and click run as administrator for the first time
On linux and mac just open Blender as per usual
We can install the add on by opening the preferences in Blender, and installing the Text to Speech zip file
It might take a moment to install the text to speech library
In linux you also need to open a terminal and copy paste the following command
The command can be found in the video description
When you navigate to the video editing interface you should see the Text to Speech tab
If it doesn't appear, you can toggle the system console to see any errors in Windows
In linux and mac you need to open Blender from a terminal to see any errors
Let me know if you have any issues
You can make individual audio strips by typing something in the text field and pressing Text to Speech
Alternatively you can import a closed caption file and it will convert all the strips to audio
Voice, pitch and rate can be chosen before converting text to speech
Currently only text files, s.r.t and s.b.v files are supported
If time codes are provided, audio strips will be placed at that time
In the case of txt files, audio strips will be placed one after another
After importing, you can move the audio strips around, delete them, and mix with individual audio strips
You can then export closed caption files and it will export an updated file that corresponds to your current audio strips
You can save blender, reopen and it will remember the text associated with the audio strips for further editing
Thanks for watching
Let me know if you have any issues!