If you're using Windows, you will need to right click blender and click run as administrator for the first time
On Linux and Mac just open Blender as per usual
We can install the add on by opening the preferences in Blender, and installing the Text to Speech zip file from the add on menu
It might take a moment to install the text to speech library
In linux you also need to open a terminal and copy paste the following command
The command can be found in the video description
When you navigate to the video editing interface you should see the Text to Speech tab
If it doesn't appear, you can toggle the system console to see any errors in Windows
In linux and mac you need to open Blender from a terminal to see any errors
You can make individual audio strips by typing something in the text field and pressing Text to Speech
Alternatively you can import a closed caption file and it will convert all the strips to audio
Currently text, csv, srt and sbv files are supported
voice
pitch
and rate
can be chosen before converting text to speech
You can edit captions, move them around and add new ones
caption data is saved to the blendfile
You can then export closed caption files and it will export an updated file that corresponds to your current audio strips
Thanks for watching!